Hello, my name is Adrian, and this
is a demo for the project Momento.
Momento is a tool that allows pack
makers and mod authors to add audio logs
to their mods and mod packs for lore.
Right clicking the momento item or
triggering the /dialogue command
will begin the audio playback,
and a text box will appear on the
player screen with subtitles that
will sync along to the audio.
To get started, create a resource
pack that a Momento will use
to create your dialogues.
You can use any audio recorder that
you'd like to make your audio, and then
you'll need to export it as a .OGG file.
Add this sound like you would
any other sound and remember the
reference to it that you created
it and your sounds.json file.
Next you'll need to create a
dialogue and subtitle file.
The dialogue file must be placed under
assets//momento/dialogue
. It's a JSON file, which you
can learn how to configure.
Over on our Wiki at
modrinth.com/mod/momento.
And clicking the Wiki link.
For your subtitle file, you
can use a tool like Descript to
transcribe your audio automatically,
creating matching subtitles.
Export your file as a .SRT file
and place it in assets//momento/srt/en_us.
You can replace en_us with
whatever language you'd like
to create your subtitles in.
Add this resource back to your
resources folder and start your game.
In the creative menu, you should
see a brand new momento item.
That's the end of the tutorial.
If you have any other questions,
feel free to stop by our discord
at discord.terrarium.earth
if you like this mod, please
consider supporting us on
Kofi at kofi.terrarium.earth.
Thank you for listening, and I
hope you enjoy using momento.